（富豪音乐）
-[播音员]斯坦福大学。
-欢迎来到斯坦福CS193p。
这是2020年春季季度。
我是Paul Hegarty，我将成为您的导游
冒险开发应用程序
适用于使用SwiftUI的iOS。
这个季度将是一次冒险
因为你们没人跟我在校园里
这让我很难过。
这会有点奇怪。
我相信这对你们所有人来说都会很奇怪。
并不会真的对我们造成太大影响
在这个过程中，信不信由你，
因为大多数沟通
你我之间正在发生的事
通过我们的课堂论坛Piazza。
所以你绝对想上广场
在那里问问题。
别害羞。
我们在这里得到非常快速的答复。
看看同学们也在问什么。
而且一定是在找我的帖子
因为所有课程资料，所有公告
将通过广场制作。
因此，请不要错过这一部分。
现在，所有的演讲都将被预先录制
就这样
我想那对你会方便
因为他们出来之后
你可以在闲暇时看他们
并快进和快退。
特别是由于我要进行很多演示，
那将是非常有价值的。
我想这也会带来很大的好处
就像我们在本课程中做过很多次一样
我们将课程免费发布给全世界。
这样人们就可以观看。
基本上在这里监视我们
正如我们在斯坦福大学上的课程一样。
我们会再做一次
在执行标准隐藏式字幕后
和其他后期制作工作。
因此，如果您在斯坦福大学外面看我，
也欢迎您。
现在，您当然无法参加
在论坛上与其他斯坦福大学的学生一起
因为您稍后再看。
但是有基于社区的资源
在世界各地问问题
例如堆栈溢出。
因此，当然也要去检查一下。
这个SwiftUI东西是全新的，
从字面上看只是几个月。
因此，您处于技术的最前沿
在为iOS开发应用程序时。
当你学到这一点时，
有些事情会让您熟悉。
有一点
那里的面向对象编程。
您将要学习的这种语言有点像C。
它也与Java之类的语言共享一些语法。
这样就很熟悉了。
但是你可能会学习
也为您提供了一些全新的东西。
例如，您将要学习
一种新的编程语言Swift。
我敢肯定，几乎对你们所有人来说都是全新的。
而这种编程语言
它支持面向对象的编程，
它还支持另一种编程
称为函数式编程
或面向协议的编程。
而且我不会假设你知道。
因此，我将一路教给您所有有关这方面的知识。
用户界面范例也称为反应式。
它是声明性的而不是命令性的。
我要解释这一切的意思
所以这对您来说是新的。
并且可能还有其他一些新主题。
例如，我希望涵盖
iOS的面向对象的数据库
这真的是很酷的技术。
但无论如何，您将在本课程中学到的所有知识
真的只是一种调查课程
或实际应用程序的集合
您在这里的其他CS课中正在学习的东西。
显然，例如，计算机人机界面。
API设计和语言设计。
动画，持久性，网络，多线程，
所有这些都在这里列出
绝对会是东西
我们在本课程中包括的内容。
因此，您将一起看到这一切
在现实环境中。
所以让我们谈谈
课程的机制
就像它实际会如何播放。
在这些预先录制的演讲中，
我将尝试并花费大部分时间进行演示。
我真的相信演示。
我认为它们使概念非常具体。
因此，我可能会在演示上花费大约2/3的时间。
但是有时候我确实必须去看幻灯片。
这是为了涵盖概念
如果您不了解它们，
演示可能没有任何意义。
举例来说，在第二堂课的开头，
我将介绍MVVM，设计范例
我们用来组织代码。
我还将介绍Swift中的类型系统
因为这对于理解至关重要
Swift的工作原理，以了解其类型系统。
但是，如果可以的话，我总是倾向于演示
因为我们想度过我们的时间
实际在做iOS开发。
这就是我们在这里学习的内容。
就您而言，您将需要阅读一些内容
前三周。
这主要是为了学习Swift语言。
有在线Swift编程参考手册
我将在前三个星期指导您
尝试并有效地帮助您。
因为它是一个很大的文件
我不希望你花钱
在那里的时间过长。
但是出于同样的原因，您必须了解Swift
能够做SwiftUI。
当然会有编程作业。
它们通常大约一周。
一共有四五个。
这个季度有点短，从一个星期晚开始。
所以这四五个编程任务
将在头六周内。
原因是我离开了最后三个星期
供您完成最终项目。
这个最终的项目是高潮
你学到的一切，
这样我们就没有任何编程任务
在最后的三个星期中。
如果您访问在线论坛，课程论坛，
那里还有很多信息。
教学大纲在那里发布
所以我鼓励你阅读
如果您还没有的话。
希望你有。
让我们从这里开始构建我们的第一个应用程序。
我有一个录像带
我们将要构建的第一个应用程序的外观。
这就是它的样子。
这是纸牌配对游戏。
那些在视频中看过本课程的人
过去会承认这一点。
但是当然这都是用SwiftUI编写的
因此它是一个全新的应用程序。
而且它具有比以前更多的功能。
在SwiftUI中，有些事情确实很容易做到。
因此，您可以看到它有很多动画。
这些卡正在翻转。
数字飞来飞去
当您匹配和错配卡片时。
你有那个小小的彩色戒指
在后台旋转。
因此，我们将在本课程中做很多动画工作。
动画对于良好的移动用户界面非常重要。
您还可以看到该应用程序的
多个主题，不同的颜色。
我们有那个万圣节版本。
这里有这些标志。
我们的卡片仅显示表情符号。
显然我那里的小视频
很快就会四处点击，
但您正在通过视频观看
这样您就可以备份并暂停
并仔细看一些动画
以及那里正在发生的事情。
这就是我们要花费的
在演示中最初的两三个星期
并在您的家庭作业中致力于构建此应用程序。
顺便说一句，你可能不会见我
在本季度的剩余时间里
因为我们要进行屏幕记录。
这样您就可以听到我无形的声音。
顺便说一下，我无形的声音
听起来会有些不同
因为我要用我的AirPods
当我做屏幕录像时。
它减少了鼠标点击的次数
然后敲击键盘等等。
所以，如果您在本季度的剩余时间里再也没有看到我，
享受我无形的声音。
因此，我们所做的所有工作
将被放在一个名为Xcode的应用程序中。
这是iOS的开发环境
包罗万象。
它包括源代码编辑编译器，
调试器，一切都集中在一处。
您可以从App Store免费获得它
如果您只是在Mac上进入App Store
并搜索Xcode。
您会发现这可能是第一场比赛。
您可以在这里看到它。
当您启动Xcode时，它会看起来像这样。
现在，您第一个任务的第一个必需任务
是重现我所做的一切
在前两个讲座中。
因此，您可能想暂停此视频并下载Xcode
并准备跟着我。
或者您可以在闲暇时观看此视频，
浸泡一下然后回去
然后倒带，快进
来满足第一个必需的任务。
因此，在此初始屏幕中，它具有两个方面。
这是将要建立的近期项目
随着季度的进行。
然后，从本质上讲，这就是我们进入项目的方式。
我们将在这里选择第二行
创建一个新的Xcode项目。
现在，可以像我们前面提到的那样使用Xcode，
不仅适用于iOS应用，还适用于Watch应用
和Apple TV应用程序，甚至只是Mac应用程序。
在本课程中，我们将专注于构建iOS应用，
但是您所学到的关于SwiftUI的一切，
它也适用于所有其他平台。
现在，这些图标都只是模板。
本质上，预包装的少量代码
让您开始使用某些类型的应用。
但是我们将选择Single View App
我认为本季度每个应用程序。
这是最简单的模板
你会发现它真的不会产生
很多代码可以帮助您入门。
因此，我们双击它。
现在，它想知道一些有趣的事情
有关您的应用的信息，尤其是名称。
因此，我将其称为“记忆”。
对于那些可能正在观看此内容的人
谁看过以前的视频
本课程过去的四分之一，
您会知道我以前做过这个记忆匹配游戏。
显然在SwiftUI中不是，因为那是全新的。
我称它为专注而不是记忆。
我这样做是有原因的，使用了另一个名称
这样，如果我们想参考它，我可以提一下。
当我说专心
我的意思是旧的非Swiftift版本。
而做相同的应用程序将允许你们
谁可能已经知道一些UIKit
或有一些这样做的经验
比较和对比外观
在SwiftUI中做到这一点。
所以这第二件事，团队，
那就是您的开发团队。
在这种情况下，这是一个个人团队，只有我一个人。
当您启动Xcode时，
这可能会说类似添加团队。
当您单击它时，只需输入任何Apple ID
您可以创建自己的团队。
如果你在一家公司工作，
它可能是这里的公司开发团队。
组织名称，这是您的名字。
这将出现在文件的顶部，
由CS193p讲师编写。
所以你想把你的名字放在那里。
这想成为您的唯一标识符。
因此，如果您是斯坦福大学的学生，
我建议使用这种反向DNS表示法。
edu.stanford.yoursunetid可能足够好
识别你
如果需要，可以将CS193p放在其中。
如果您是斯坦福大学的学生，那可能没关系。
如果您不是斯坦福大学的学生，并且正在观看此视频，
也许您的电子邮件地址已反转
或您公司的地址颠倒了。
您只想确保它是唯一的。
你不会想要挑东西
其他人也可能会选择。
您可能会看到Xcode使这个唯一标识符
这两个方面为您的应用程序所用。
然后我们要选择语言。
iOS的基础
都是用Objective-C语言编写的，
这是C的面向对象版本。
但是大约五六年前
苹果公司推出了这种新语言Swift，
很棒，因为它是完全兼容的
使用Objective-C。
因此，所有现有的库都可以正常工作。
但是它引入了许多现代语言功能，
特别是对函数式编程的支持
与面向对象的编程相反。
斯威夫特做到了，你真的会看到
在SwiftUI中，因为SwiftUI基于
函数式编程，而不是面向对象的编程。
所以我没有时间教你两种语言
我几乎没有时间教你一个新的。
因此，我们只会在Swift中进行编程。
当然，SwiftUI都是基于Swift的Swift。
其他用户界面选择
如果你想以旧的方式发展，
非SwiftUI方法。
我经常将这个UIKit称为SwiftUI。
我们将在SwiftUI中进行所有开发，
尽管该季度的最后一两个星期，
希望我有时间告诉你
如何将旧内容集成到SwiftUI中。
因为SwiftUI不能覆盖所有领域
旧的UIKit可以做到。
因此，能够在其中粘贴它真是太好了。
因此，SwiftUI中有一些很好的粘合剂
粘上UIKit的东西。
底部的其他开关，
我们可能会在本季度末获得时间
做这个核心数据。
这是一个面向对象的数据库。
我希望有时间这样做。
不幸的是，我可能没有时间
做这个测试框架。
我真的不想让它听起来像
测试并不重要。
这非常重要。
只是您无法真正测试某些东西
直到你知道如何发展
我们将要用光时间
在我回去掩盖之前。
因此，对于我们的第一个任务，
我们不会做任何这些
因此您可以取消所有选择。
所以我在这里点击下一步，现在它想知道，
“很好，您想创建这个应用程序。
“你想放在哪里？”
我强烈建议将其放在文件夹中
在您的主目录中称为Developer。
那就是我们放置事物的规范位置。
我强烈建议您这样做。
在这里的底部
您可以看到此“源代码管理”内容。
针对您的源代码控制
谁不熟悉
这是您管理代码更改的一种方式，
签入然后签出。
有团队的时候特别有价值
因为团队正在使用相同的代码，
他们的更改可能会发生冲突或其他情况。
因此，您想要一种仲裁这些更改的机制。
因此，您可以选择是否选中此选项。
我不会在这里检查它。
在本季度晚些时候，我会尝试去
通过一些功能
源代码管理集成
在Xcode中，因为它非常酷。
但就目前而言，任何一种方法都可以。
因此，这将创建我们的第一个应用程序。
现在，你们中的许多人都不熟悉
通过整个用户界面，
此Xcode用户界面。
所以我要简短地讲一下
我将从左上角开始
就在这里，这小排按钮。
本质上，这就是我们运行应用程序的方式。
现在，如果您单击此处的此按钮，
您会看到可以在设备上运行应用程序
如果您实际将其连接到Mac
我目前没有。
或者，您可以在模拟器中运行它。
这些模拟器非常棒。
他们是一个完整的模拟
我要在这里告诉你
而且我实际上将选择iPhone 11作为我的模拟器。
我可以运行这个SwiftUI应用
通过单击“播放”为我创建的模板。
因此，当我单击“播放”按钮时，
它会启动模拟器。
现在，第一次您这样做
这会花费一些时间
因为模拟器可以完全模拟设备。
实际上，我将向您展示。
所以这是我们的应用程序，它说：“你好，世界！”
您可能可以从这里的这段代码中想象出来。
这就是所有第一个应用程序所做的，他们说“ Hello，World”。
但是如果我们从底部向上滑动
就像在真实设备上一样
您可以看到这里有应用选择器
我可以进入“设置”
这是“设置”应用
我可以设置设备的设置等等。
这不是100％完整的设备，
但这是您需要的设备部分
以确保您的应用程序确实有效。
我不知道您是否还注意到该设备
相似，它恰好在黑暗模式下
这是iOS 13中的新功能。
我要留在黑暗模式
因为我们要看我们的应用程序
在黑暗模式和非黑暗模式下都可以。
SwiftUI为我们处理了大部分此类工作。
所以我要回到这里的应用切换器
然后切换回我们的应用
它在这里说：“你好，世界！”
让我们回头看看我们如何做到这一点。
我们如何处理整个您好，世界事务。
所以我要在这里按这个正方形。
这是停止，停止模拟器。
让我们继续看一下Xcode的UI。
在这里的左边，这个小小的蓝色区域
我们可以将其调整为所需的大小。
它称为导航器。
它使您可以按文件导航。
因此，您可以单击此处的文件。
但它也可以让您导航
沿顶部的所有其他方式。
就像您可以通过搜索进行导航。
您可以在调试器中浏览断点。
您可以浏览所有旧版本，
旧版本的输出等等。
所以您真的会习惯使用导航器
在应用内移动
找到您想要的东西，等等。
现在，在右侧，这是灰色区域。
这称为实用程序窗口
或有时我们称为检查专员。
我们真的不需要那么多
我们的前几讲。
所以我实际上要利用这个机会
向您展示如何隐藏它。
如果您查看右上方的这三个按钮，
它们使您可以隐藏和显示这些窗格。
而且我实际上要隐藏实用程序
因为就像我说的，我们不需要太多。
您会看到这里有第三个按钮。
这实际上从底部带来了一些好处。
这是您的调试器，控制台输出在这里。
我倾向于让那些不在屏幕上
只是因为他们浪费屏幕房地产
如果我没有真正调试。
而且，他们经常会自动自行出现
例如，当您在调试器中命中断点
或控制台上出现一些输出。
这个区域是主编辑窗口。
您会看到它目前分为两部分。
而且，您可以根据需要以多种方式划分该区域。
这就是这里的小加号按钮的功能。
它使您可以在右侧添加另一个第三个编辑器。
您甚至可以在底部添加一个编辑器
如果您希望将拆分结果放在最下面，等等。
这就是我们对Xcode UI的浏览。
当然这里有很多菜单项
我们将在季度进行中了解它们。
但是让我们看一下我们的主要编辑窗口
看看我们得到了什么。
您在这里看到的是这个ContentView.swift。
这是一个Swift文件。
因此，这是您第一次了解Swift语言。
我将从这小段代码开始。
这小段代码做什么
是否提供一些胶水
您正在编写的代码之间
和右边的这个小区域
这称为“预览”窗口。
看，它说自动预览更新已暂停。
当然，我们有模拟器。
我们总是可以运行它来查看我们的应用程序
看起来像
但是我们也可以看到UI中正在发生的事情，
通过点击此处的“ Resume”，大约可以实时实现。
而这将是编译我们的代码
基本上就在这里运行
看起来有点像iPhone。
请注意，这不是在黑暗模式下
因此文字为黑底白字。
而且这是自动的，SwiftUI会为我们解决这一问题。
我们也可以调整大小。
也许在这里做，它的空间会更少。
这段代码本质上就是粘在它上面的，
我真的不会对此给予太多关注。
实际上，我将其移开。
当您进行这样的大编辑时
或者您要移动很多代码，
有时此预览会暂停。
您知道，它再次暂停了。
没问题，您可以恢复。
但是您进行了许多更改，
就像我更改此“ Hello，World！”
成为“你好，世界！”
您会看到它实际上是实时更改它。
所以这取决于变化的种类
您正在编写代码
是否会实时更新。
同样，您始终可以运行模拟器。
特别是如果你想看
在许多不同的设备和类似的东西上。
您随时都可以使用模拟器。
因此，让我们看一下Swift代码。
这就是Swift代码的全部
这是特定于我们的应用程序的。
这里有一些样板
在这两个委托中。
我们稍后再看
但这实际上是几乎所有的一切
说到“ Hello，World”就在这里。
因此，让我们详细了解一下Swift代码。
首先，我们有此导入SwiftUI。
我相信你们都可以确切地想象那是什么。
就像包含或导入其他语言一样。
这将在Swift中导入所谓的包。
这个包是SwiftUI。
这就是Apple提供的大包
这使得所有SwiftUI都可以正常工作。
因此，无论何时我们做UI事情，
我们总是会导入SwiftUI。
有时我们会写代码
那不是UI的东西。
实际上，是有意UI无关的。
在这种情况下，我们将不会导入SwiftUI。
我们将导入其他软件包
叫做基金会。
Foundation是一种数组，字典和字符串。
SwiftUI包取决于Foundation。
因此，如果您导入SwiftUI，
您也会自动得到那个。
所以这整个过程实际上只是三行代码，
不包括花括号。
让我们看看它是什么。
这里的第一个关键词。
请注意，所有Swift关键字均为洋红色。
我们总是可以分辨出Swift的区别
以及我们所做的事情。
所以这是一个结构。
这只是声明一个结构。
现在，我确定您知道一种具有结构的语言。
C和C ++以及这些语言都有结构。
和其他语言一样，Swift中的结构
是一些变量的容器。
但是Swift中的结构要强大得多。
Swift中的结构不仅可以有变量，
但是他们可以有功能
他们也可以有行为
我们将非常清楚地看到
就在这里。
因此，此结构的名称为ContentView。
因此，标识符的名称为绿色。
Swift的标识符为紫色
关键字再次变为洋红色。
因此，此结构的名称为ContentView。
这是非常有趣的一小部分
该结构的声明。
它本质上意味着这个结构
会表现得像View。
也许有人会说它会像View一样起作用。
甚至有人甚至会说它是“视图”。
尽管如果我使用“是”视图的声明，
有些人会认为这是面向对象的编程
像超类之类的东西。
但事实并非如此。
这不是面向对象的编程。
这是功能编程。
这就是为什么我们更有可能
说类似ContentView之类的功能
或表现得像View。
这是非常重要的。
视图这种行为至关重要
您将看到所有SwiftUI的工作方式。
我们将使用很多视图
在接下来的两节课中，您甚至无法想象。
我们将讨论所有概念
该行为规范的背后
在第二讲的开头使用幻灯片。
同时，我们将要了解
这意味着ContentView的行为类似于View。
视图只是屏幕上的一个矩形区域。
所以在这里我将鼠标放在此文本上
并在预览中选择了它。
您会看到它在该文本周围放置了蓝色边框。
该蓝色边框与该视图接壤。
因此，文本的行为也类似于视图。
它是一个“视图”。
因此，您正在这里看到它。
这就是所有视图。
它们是屏幕上的矩形区域，
既用于绘画，也用于多点触控。
对于滑动和水龙头，捏，
这些事情发生在这些矩形中。
这就是视图。
因此，当某物的行为类似于View时，
这是屏幕上的矩形区域。
所以我们的ContentView就像View
是整个矩形吗？
充满屏幕的整个矩形
是我们的ContentView。
好吧，如果你是某人，
像ContentView这样的结构
并且您想说自己的行为类似于View，
你必须在你的结构体中有这个变量，
这个变种叫做身体。
我会在这里为您选择。
这是var body的声明。
因此Swift变量有关键字var，
变量的缩写。
虽然我们不倾向于调用变量
像这样的var里面的结构。
我们称它们为属性。
所以您会一直听到我使用property一词。
它表示结构或类中的var。
另外，如果我们在进行面向对象的编程，
我们称它们为属性。
因此，属性的语法真的很简单，您有了一个var。
这是属性的名称。
同样，它是绿色的，因为这是我们选择的东西。
这就是此属性的类型
或这个变种
现在，即使在Swift中，这也是一个非常有趣的类型。
因为它有一个洋红色的关键字
在它的中间。
通常，此类型可能看起来像是一个Int
也许是一个字符串。
或者它可能是一个布尔值
或者它是一个数组之类的东西。
但就我们而言，这是一些观点
这是一种有趣的类型。
这本质上是什么意思
是该变量的类型，该属性，
只要它的行为类似于View，就可以是任何类型，任何结构。
只要是一些视图。
这就是这种奇怪的事情
就是这里
因此，如果您想表现得像View，
你必须有一个叫做身体的变种
这也是另一种行为，类似于View。
您可能会想，“什么？
“那真是怪了。
“因此要成为一个视图，我必须拥有一个变种
“那是我的另一种观点？
“这是没有意义的。”
但是您可以将Views视为Legos。
所以当然有一些积木
乐高积木，就像文字一样的基本事物。
文字就像一块积木。
但是，然后您可以将乐高积木组合在一起，做出其他事情。
和你把它们放在一起的东西，
您可以称其为新乐高。
这就像合并的乐高玩具或更强大的乐高玩具。
例如，如果您要建造一个乐高房屋，
您可能会制作很少的乐高家具。
乐高沙发，乐高厨房桌子，
所有这些东西都来自其他乐高玩具。
如果你考虑到沙发和厨房桌子
作为乐高积木，那么你将它们放在一起
盖房子
您甚至可以让房子成为乐高积木
放在一起组成一个乐高社区。
或乐高世界，乐高宇宙。
这就是我们想要想到的方式。
现在，乐高和景观之间的区别
是有特殊的观点
用来组合乐高积木。
我们已经有了这些基本的积木，例如Text。
然后我们有其他类型的视图
就是合成器，乐高合成器，查看合成器。
您将看到我们在这里详细使用它们。
这就是为什么我们的身体刚刚恢复
一个单一的某种视图。
它可能正在返回组合器。
如果返回合并器视图，
那么里面可能会有无数的视图
结合在一起。
现在，这也是一种有趣的变种
因为它后面有这个大括号的东西。
此var，其值不存储在内存中。
而是计算此var。
因此，每当有人（即系统）
要求这个变量的值，
花括号中的此代码将被执行。
无论返回什么值，
这就是身体的价值所在。
每次调用它时，都会再次调用它，
它一直在叫这个东西。
现在，这里的代码似乎有点简单
但这可能更有意义
如果我把这个关键字放回去。
此关键字返回，您会看到洋红色。
这是一个迅速的事情，这意味着回报。
从这段代码中返回一个值，
这小段花括号的代码。
它不在那里是因为Swift喜欢把事情遗漏掉
并使其成为必需，因此您必须键入尽可能少的代码。
您稍后会看到。
因此，如果您具有这样的单行功能
返回一个值，这就是这个，
单行返回此Text内容。
然后，您可以将其退回。
只是推断一下。
但是我要留在里面
因为我要你意识到
那就是这里正在发生的事情。
我们有这小段代码，
它返回这个Text的东西。
那将永远是身体的价值。
每当有人问我身体的价值时，
它会执行此命令并在此处返回此文本。
现在，请记住，此返回类型是一些View。
因此，如果您说的是：“它正在返回Text。
“这里发生了什么？”
好吧，当然是Text，它说它的行为就像View。
这就是“某些视图”。
换句话说，在苹果代码的某个地方
有一些看起来像这样的线。
“结构文本的行为类似于视图。”
这就是为什么我们可以将Text作为body的值返回的原因
因为这是一些观点。
实际上，我们甚至可以在此处键入Text。
这将是有效的，因为其行为类似于View，
您的var主体只需返回一个View视图。
当然，文本是视图。
那么，为什么不键入Text？
我们为什么要这样做一些视图？
好吧，随着我们的观点变得越来越复杂
然后我们开始使用这些View-combiners
诸如此类的事情将会不断变化。
我们要返回哪种视图。
现在，我们正在返回文本。
但最终我们要回来了
视图合并视图。
我们想让编译器为我们解决问题。
因此，这种观点基本上是对编译器说的，
“在这里查看我的代码。
“弄清楚它返回了什么。
“确保它的行为类似于View。
“然后将其用作身体的类型。”
您将在我们完成本课程的过程中找到
Swift是一种非常强类型的语言。
这意味着每个变量都有特定的类型。
它不是JavaScript或其他语言
哪里好，变量
取决于您为其分配的内容。
到那时候...
不，在Swift中，每个变量都有特定的类型
并始终具有价值。
这只是Swift运作方式的基础。
因此，让我们在这里查看此文本。
我们创建此文本。
每当我们创建任何东西，任何结构，
因此，文本只是行为类似于视图的结构。
每当我们创建一个时，我们都会用括号括起来
给它提供创建自己所需的任何信息。
现在，显然对于文本
它需要用于创建自身的字符串。
这就是为什么您得到这个“ Hello There，World！”的原因。
并且请注意，如果我编辑了它，它并没有改变。
那是因为它在这里暂停了。
但是如果我恢复，那将会
现在我可以输入例如，它正在跟踪它。
因此，这始终是我们创建任何类型的新结构的方式。
我们在它后面加上括号
然后我们给它任何想要的参数。
在创建它们时，还有一些事情，
可以接受不同种类的论点
取决于它们是什么。
您很快就会在这里看到的。
让我们看看是否可以开始构建
看起来更像卡片的UI。
现在它只是说：“你好，世界！”
让我们提醒自己自己会是什么样子。
游戏的屏幕截图
我刚才给你看的
还有我们的卡片，它们都有这些圆角矩形
在边缘，你看到了吗？
这是一条线。
然后是白色背景。
他们的前面有一个表情符号。
因此，让我们照顾所有这些事情。
让我们从表情符号开始。
那真的很容易
因为表情符号只是一段文字。
所以我要删除它。
我不知道您是否知道，但是在任何Mac应用程序中，
如果您进入“修改”菜单，请转到底部，
会有表情符号和符号。
你看那里，我可以得到一个表情符号。
您甚至可以搜索幽灵。
在那里，鬼。
让我们双击它。
现在我们有个鬼。
可以肯定的是，有我们的幽灵。
他真的很小。
尽管我们可以放大并在那里看到他。
而且我们将不得不解决他这么小。
这不会为我们的卡工作
像他那么小
但是一次只有一件事。
接下来我们需要的是圆角矩形。
因此，我们需要一个圆角矩形，它会向上移动。
因此，让我们将此文本注释掉。
所以我在那边做Command斜线
评论该文本。
而是将我们的圆角矩形放在那里。
幸运的是，Swift在这里有很棒的东西。
RoundedRectangle正是我们想要的。
同样，就像我们创建文本时一样，
我们必须提供一些信息
创建RoundedRectangle。
顺便说一句，您可以轻松找出是什么
只做开括号
Xcode将为您显示选项。
现在，RoundedRectangle有四种不同的方式
创建一个ZStack。
您可以指定拐角半径或拐角大小，
角的宽度和高度。
我要去cornerRadius。
因此，您可以在此处单击Tab，也可以双击它。
然后，它需要半径，以磅为单位。
所以我要做10分。
点与字体的点大小相同，
像10点字体。
也只是为了让您了解一个点的大小，
典型的iPhone可能是四或500点宽
也许是七或八百点高
iPad可能是1,000 x 700。
现在，我故意在这里模糊
因为我们从不编写代码
试图知道屏幕的尺寸是多少。
SwiftUI帮助我们编写代码
适用于任何尺寸的屏幕。
它只是适应和调整任何尺寸的屏幕。
您真的会在我们的记忆游戏中看到这一点
当我们开始有行和列的按钮时。
在大屏幕上，它们会变大。
当我们处于人像模式时，它将改变大小
一种方法，另一种景观。
所以我们总是想写我们的代码
因此它可以在任何尺寸的屏幕上使用。
但这是一个点的大概大小
给你一个观点
现在，这件事有点奇怪
这是这里吗
它在这条信息上贴了标签
它需要创建一个ZStack。
而Text并没有发生这种情况。
这不是说字符串或类似的东西。
文字没有这些之一。
但这实际上是常态。
像文本这样的东西很不寻常
这里没有标签作为参数。
您必须全力以赴。
我要告诉你如何摆脱困境
尽管我们不会经常这样做。
相反，当我们创建事物时，
当我们传递信息时，
我们几乎总是给每块贴上标签。
当我们调用函数时也是如此。
所以可能需要做的一件事
最习惯于Swift
是几乎所有的论点
所有功能的所有参数都被标记。
这是从Objective-C继承的。
其实很好，因为如果我们没有这个
我们有ZStack 10，
我的意思是，宽度和高度
或那十是多少？
但是只要我们把这个角半径放到那里，
突然之间，“哦，我在创造
“ ZStack的拐角半径为10。”
很难看到我们的矩形是否在此圆角。
那是因为我实际上选择了这一行代码。
所以我们这里有一条蓝线。
但是如果我点击离开
那么您现在可以开始在那里看到ZStack。
如果我放大，可以看到
ZStack很清楚。
显然，我们将不得不做一些事情
关于此可见性。
我们的卡不想撞到边缘
而且他们也不想变黑。
但是首先是第一件事。
我们将稍作讨论。
我想做的下一件事是结合
这个RoundedRectangle和这个Text在一起。
因为请记住，我们的卡片都具有RoundedRectangle
和一个文本堆叠在一起。
我将不得不通过返回一些View来做到这一点。
所以我要在这里返回的视图称为ZStack。
因此，ZStack只是一个结构。
它的行为就像View
就像RoundedRectangle是一个结构
行为就像一个视图。
文字也是如此。
实际上，我们的ContentView也是如此。
ZStack确实需要在此处创建一个参数。
我们要使用的参数是内容，然后大括号
彼此堆叠的视图列表。
显然，我们不需要这里的退货。
这就是清单。
后面是RoundedRectangle，前面是Text。
列表中的第一件事，这是两个项目
但是我们可以有五六个或七个
所有列在一行中，它将全部堆叠
在彼此之上。
ZStack只是一些视图。
实际上，这里的返回类型
这里是某种ZStack
而不是Text或RoundedRectangle
或类似的东西。
但是Swift会自动实现
它正在返回这个。
因此，它将为我们做到这一点。
这种组合视图显然很重要
建立复杂的视图。
下周我们将构建自己的合并器视图。
所以您真的要了解这些事情是如何工作的。
现在，我们到了。
但是还有一些事情，我们这里会继续介绍，
看起来不太像我们的卡片。
首先，我们的卡上没有黑色。
它们在外部被橙色打动。
还有一个问题，就是很难看到边缘
因为他们一直走到了边缘。
因此，让我们修复这两个问题。
首先，让我们抚摸一下而不是填充它。
而我们要做的方式
是我们要调用一个函数
在RoundedRectangle上称为笔触。
RoundedRectangle，我们知道它的行为类似于View。
它的行为必须类似于View
否则我们将无法将其放入ZStack
喜欢这个文字。
但是RoundedRectangle也表现得像另一件事
这是一个形状。
其他形状包括圆形，胶囊形，贝塞尔曲线形，
这些都是形状。
和形状都可以抚摸
通过在它们上调用此函数称为stroke。
您会看到这正是发生的情况。
它在边缘划了一条线
此RoundedRectangle。
中风是一个有趣的功能
它返回了一些东西。
你能猜出它返回什么吗？
它返回一个视图。
它返回的行为类似于View。
它必须这样做，因为无论它是什么，都必须是一个视图。
否则，我们不能将其放入ZStack中。
所以这就像抚摸
RoundedRectangle视图或类似的东西。
因此，ZStack中仍然有两个视图。
描边的RoundedRectangle是其中之一
文本是另一个。
因此，这种在View上调用函数的模式
或形状
返回另一个View是很常见的。
这是您第一次看到Swift函数调用。
确实很简单，只是点和函数的名称。
然后在括号中加上任何参数。
现在，中风实际上可以引起争论
但没有它的论点，它可以很好地工作。
没有论据，
这只是某种默认行为
轻描淡写的单点线
形状的边缘周围。
那颜色呢
RoundedRectangle的边缘在这里？
目前看来
可能是深灰色或类似的东西。
如果我们希望它变成橙色怎么办？
那么我们该怎么做呢？
好吧，这是一个视图，在这里是一些视图。
所有视图，任何表现得像视图的东西，
您可以在其上调用名为前景颜色的函数。
它接受一个参数，即Color。
我要用橙色。
这将设置它用来绘制的颜色
变成这个颜色，橙色。
果然，看看那个。
在那里将其更改为橙色。
现在，可以在任何视图上调用此函数。
我们可以称其为Text。
您可以看到，没有错误。
当然，它对文本没有帮助
因为这是一个表情符号。
但是如果“文字”改为字母X，
您会看到那里是一个橙色的X。
同样，在此处调用它没有任何意义。
我们可以将这个橙色发送到的另一件事是我们的ZStack。
告诉该视图意味着什么
使它的前景色是橙色的？
ZStack只是一个视图。
它的行为类似于View，因此具有前景色
就像世界上其他所有视图一样。
它的意思是“告诉每个视图
“在我内部使用前景色橙色。”
因此，这也有效。
看那个。
看，那是橙色。
再说一次，如果我们把这个鬼改成X，
X也将是橙色的，因为ZStack
本质上是在设置环境
它里面的所有视图
将用于绘制。
现在可以覆盖它。
然后我们可以说前景颜色（Color.blue）。
然后我们在这里得到一个蓝色的。
但这仍然是橙色。
因为我只覆盖了这个前景
对于此处的此视图，此描边的RoundedRectangle。
我没有在此处对此X覆盖它。
因此，通过对这些函数的调用进行范围界定，
这样我们就可以控制颜色是什么
这对于ZStack真的很有价值
因为我们最终要制造这个ZStack
所以它在纸牌的正面，纸牌的背面
在所有情况下，所有想要变成橙色的东西。
所以我们想要橙色作为一切
所以能够设置它真的很棒
对于整个ZStack。
我们通常把这些修饰符
对于这些单独的合并器视图，
只是为了让他们更加突出。
而我们可能会将它们放在同一行。
尽管偶尔，我们甚至会把这些
也放在单独的行上。
但是我们不会在这里这样做，但是您可以。
这是一种风格。
但是，您认为您的代码最具可读性
也是最容易理解的
因此，我们在这里的卡取得了良好的进展。
一件事，在这里很难看到边缘。
我们有点想在此边缘周围填充一些内容。
我们可以使用另一个View函数进行填充
称为填充。
这里要注意的是，当我在文本周围放置填充时，
哎呀，它弹出了，周围有一些填充物。
现在，我可以在这里做同样的事情
我的笔触RoundedRectangle，因为它是一个视图。
填充，哦，很好。
您看，它在其中放置了填充。
再说一次，我什至可以把填充
围绕我的整个ZStack。
它把填充物放在整个ZStack上
这可能是我想要的
因为我不想放填充物
分别在每个RoundedRectangle上。
像RoundedRectangle一样，我们将使用
最终我的卡背面等等。
因此，很高兴能够将它们放在外面。
现在，请注意填充之间的细微差别
和foregroundColor。
填充填充ZStack。
整个ZStack周围都有填充
并绘制了ZStack中的所有内容
在那小小的填充区域。
而前景色实际上没有任何意义
ZStack。
ZStack没有颜色。
它所做的全部都包含其他视图。
因此它被传递到环境中
里面的所有视图。
好吧，让我们看看
我们一直在这里查看我们的预览。
但让我们来看一下我们的模拟器
看看这看起来如何。
而且，很有意思。
它正在工作，但在这里看起来不太好。
那是因为我们的模拟器处于黑暗模式。
确实，我们希望这种背景是白色的。
即使在黑暗模式下，我们也希望它是白色的。
我们不希望它成为黑色背景上的黑卡。
假设我们希望它是白色的。
那我们怎么把那白色的呢？
不幸的是，您无法发送任何功能
改为说用一种颜色描边的RoundedRectangle
然后用另一种颜色填充它。
但这没问题，因为我们就在这里的ZStack中。
所以我要创建另一个RoundedRectangle，
而我将填充而不是中风。
记住，这就是背后的原因。
然后在这里继续。
现在，它将用前景颜色填充
在这里设置为环境，所以我什至看不到。
但幸运的是fill需要一个可选参数
这是要填充的颜色。
并在此覆盖此foregroundColor。
所以现在这是白色的。
如果单击此处，它将用白色填充。
还有那个橙色的边框，很难看清。
它只有一点宽，尤其是在黑色附近。
真的很难看到。
因此，让我们对其进行修复。
我告诉你的中风还可以接受其他论点。
可以采用的是线宽。
因此，使它的线宽为三。
同样，我们可以在此处继续以灯光模式查看它。
在那里。
我们可以在这里运行以在暗模式下进行查看。
顺便说一下，模拟器的明暗模式
也可以在这里控制
您在这里看到这个小按钮吗？
您看到此界面样式了吗？
您可以将其打开，然后从暗模式转到亮模式。
现在，如果您回到模拟器，
它处于灯光模式。
这确实是一种来回切换的好方法。
因此，我们在这里取得了很大进展。
我们的小表情符号仍然很小。
我要把它放大。
我可以用Font做到这一点。
字体，Font.largeTitle。
现在，我在这里使用一种称为罐头字体的罐头字体。
还有其他一些叫做副标题
和身体等。
largeTitle恰好是我可以找到的最大标题。
如果我们恢复，您将看到
它会使我们的表情符号更大。
仍然不够大。
下周我们将学习如何缩放字体
大小正好适合我们的卡片
但是目前至少它会变得更大一些。
我这样做的原因之一
我也想告诉你这个字体，
虽然这似乎是纯文本的事情，
它实际上可以放在ZStack上
它将为所有文本设置字体环境。
因此，如果我在ZStack中有多个Text，
那么它将使用字体，所有字体都使用该字体。
您可以轻松想象构建某些东西
有多段文字
并且您希望它们都使用相同的字体。
因此在ZStack上设置它是一个非常酷的功能
为此。
所以我有点想像这张卡。
现在我要多张卡，因为我这里只有一张卡
而且我很想拥有多张卡。
那我将如何获得多张卡？
我将通过返回另一种视图来做到这一点，
另一个合并器视图。
这称为ForEach。
现在，ForEach当然需要参数。
第一个参数，它有两个参数。
第一个参数就像某种可迭代的事物。
我们将在稍后讨论。
就像ZStack一样，第二个参数就是内容。
内容就是这个ZStack。
ForEach将会做什么
它将迭代这个可迭代的事情。
对于这些东西，
将要构建这些视图之一。
因此，它本质上是制作多个视图的一种方法。
View复制器或View迭代器的种类
如果您想这样想。
那么，我们在这里谈论的这件事是什么呢？
好吧，通常这将是一个数组。
所以你要给它一些东西
对于数组中的每个事物，
这将创建一个视图。
我不会在这里使用数组。
我们最终将切换为使用数组
但我正在使用另一种称为Range的可迭代对象。
因此，这是从零到不包括四个的范围。
这就是这里的Swift语法的含义。
表示从下限到上限的范围，
不包括上限。
如果您说点-点-点，则它包括上限。
但是我不想包含上限。
因此，这是零，一，二和三。
将在这里创建此ZStack。
因此，它是一个中继器。
现在，一件事也很酷，
因此，在具有内容的地方也是一样。
这可能是“视图”列表。
这里只有一个View，它是一个ZStack。
但是我们可能有很多事情。
就像在ZStack中一样，我们有很多事情。
ForEach，它的小花括号
可能有很多东西。
ForEach也很酷的一件事
其实这里有这个小东西吗
我们将在某个时候谈论这个“中”的含义
但这本质上是迭代变量。
因此，在这种情况下，该索引为零。
然后是一，然后是二，然后是三
因为它使得这四个。
现在，关于ForEach的一件事，
您会在实际制作的预览中看到
四个单独的预览。
那是因为ForEach不是布局视图。
它不像ZStack。
ZStack将视图放置在屏幕上
从背面到正面彼此重叠。
ForEach不会这样做，如果您运行，
如果我们要在模拟器中运行它，
可能会将View放在某处
因为它显然无法模拟多部iPhone。
但实际上预览实际上显示了更多
创建四个视图的情况。
因此，它向您展示了四种视图
它正在创造。
调试真的很酷。
就像，“哦，是的，这就是现在。”
我们的四个观点是完全一样的
所以对我们来说没那么有趣。
但是我们真正想做的是
将所有这四个同时显示在屏幕上。
为此，我们需要另一个堆栈。
现在，我们不想将它们堆叠在一起
而且我们看不到后面的东西。
相反，我们想要一个不同的
这就是我们要返回的HStack。
就像ZStack一样，我们的HStack也具有内容。
然后您将内容放入内容中
你想这样安排。
和HStack一样，而不是从头到尾地安排事情，
它水平排列东西。
这就是H从左到右的意思。
因此，从左到右看，它在那里排列。
现在，我告诉你，斯威夫特喜欢不打东西
您不需要输入。
那回报我仍然可以删除
因为信不信由你
仍然只返回一个视图。
被用作这个身体的价值，
一些视图，它是一个视图。
这是一个由ForEaches组成的HStack，用于填充ZStacks。
它具有前景色和字体。
那就是返回的那个视图。
当然，HStack是组合器，因此它正在组合东西。
ForEach是组合器，ZStack是组合器。
但是这些都在HStack内部。
现在，还要注意HStack
当看到ForEach时，因为这可能是一个列表，
我们可以说Text（“ hello”）
因此它打招呼。
然后这个ForEach就像清单
每个ZStack分别。
这就是为什么这样做。
因此，每个堆栈都很聪明。
它知道里面是否有ForEach
然后它想要布局
每个ForEach事物分别存在。
现在，这里要注意的另一件事是间距。
这些东西之间有一点空间。
这是这里的填充吗？
不，那个填充就是这个填充
在HStack的外部
因为填充函数是在HStack本身上调用的。
这个间隔实际上是HStack正在做的事情
它有一个参数可以让您进行设置。
所以在这里，我将间距设置为零。
或将其设置为50或不指定。
很多时候，我们没有指定那些东西
因为我们希望此间距为标准间距。
在所有应用程序中都相同。
在这里填充同样的事情。
我们在这里没有指定任何内容，但在填充中
您实际上甚至可以在顶部填充100。
或所有边上的填充都是10。
但是通常我们会尽可能地使用标准填充。
标准填充和间距。
现在，我告诉您，记得我们带走了这份退货。
我们可以拿走另一件事。
在Swift中，如果函数的最后一个参数
或某物的创造，所以这里是ForEach。
它有两个参数。
此后再将其作为第二个参数。
如果第二个参数是大括号，
信不信由你，你可以摆脱标签
并将其放在函数调用之外。
这就是ForEach。
因此基本上就是ForEach的创建。
这是它的第二个论点。
它浮在括号之外。
因此，这似乎有点疯狂。
但是实际上，看起来它使我们的代码看起来像什么。
我要为所有这些事情做
因为这只有一个论点。
所以我要摆脱它。
我将在这里为我的HStack做同样的事情。
因此，这看起来更清洁。
您那里没有这些内容。
更重要的是，如果您没有争论，
在那种情况下，你有一个小花括号的家伙
在那里闲逛，您也可以将其删除。
这样就可以大大清理我们的代码。
当然，我们正在做这些ZStack
这些HStack一直都在
现在，如果我想重新设置间距，我可以。
间距为零，非常好。
它仍然是第一个论点。
这仍然是HStack的第二个论点。
所以有点清理。
所以我们的代码看起来已经很干净了
制作这四张牌。
我们可以再清理一点
通过剔除我们的一些代码。
这里的ZStack本质上就是一张卡。
如果我刚刚创建一个新结构，那会很酷吗
称为CardView的行为也类似于View？
什么意思
它必须具有某种View的var主体。
在这里，我们只返回一些视图。
我要归还ZStack。
从那里切下，粘贴到那里。
然后在ContentView中，
我只是要创建一个CardView。
所以这是我们可以使用视图的一种方式
分解出我们的代码进行封装。
使我们的代码看起来更简单，更好。
有人在看这个ContentView，
真的很容易看出来。
同样在这里。
简单看。
现在，本课我要做的最后一件事
是做卡的正面和背面。
因为现在，我们只显示了卡的正面。
我们永远不会显示卡的背面。
那么，我们将如何抽回这张卡呢？
好吧，它也是ZStack
但它充满了前台颜色。
所以我们实际上可以继续
然后复制并粘贴到这里
将RoundedRectangle用作背面。
现在，我将对此进行评论。
当然，我们也不想用白色填充。
我们只是想填充我们的环境颜色是什么。
它将从这里得到。
注意，这个前景色
不仅适用于HStack中的所有内容
ForEach将其传递下去
使其适用于CardView
传递下去。
这适用于ZStack
传递下去
这样它就适用于所有这些东西。
所以现在，如果我们恢复。
我们可以看到卡片背面。
看，这是我们卡片的背面。
就在这里，刚刚填充的RoundedRectangles。
但是，当然，我们确实希望拥有前沿的业务
和卡片背面某种程度上是有条件的。
或者卡朝上或朝下。
因此，我们需要一个if-then或其他东西。
好吧，这里令人惊奇的是，这个ZStack
这允许您在此处放置视图列表
还可以让您放置ifs。
所以你可以放简单的ifs like
假设现在是isFaceUp。
我们将这三件事放在isFaceUp案例中。
然后，如果面朝下，
然后我们将其放在此处。
所以我们实际上可以放一个if。
现在，我们在这里遇到各种错误和警告
因为我刚刚编造了isFaceUp。
没关系
我只是编造的。
我要的是FaceUp吗？
好吧，我只是要一个变种。
这在内存中会是正常的。
它不会有任何花括号或任何东西。
这只是内存中的正常变量。
您会看到这里修复了我们所有的代码。
CardView是完美的，内部自洽的。
意思是说我的isFaceUp var是否为真，
然后这样，否则就这样。
但这确实在这里引起了错误。
这个错误是关于什么的，
isFaceUp是否缺少参数？
为什么这么说呢？
好吧，我早先告诉过你。
Swift，所有变量，它是强类型的
并且所有变量都必须具有初始值。
所以我们可以设置一个初始值
只是说这等于假。
如果我说这将在这里修复此错误。
面朝上是假的，这样做。
如果我将此FaceFaceUp更改为true并恢复，
现在我们获得面朝上的卡片。
所以这是设置它的一种方法。
如果可行，我们通常会设置它。
但是如果我们不在这里设置它，
我们没有给它一个默认值，
那是我们在这里收到此错误的时间。
因为Swift在说这个CardView
您正在尝试在此处创建的内容，
它具有一个未初始化的变量。
因此，您必须对其进行初始化。
这是一个很酷的功能。
如果您点击该红色错误小按钮，
很多时候，您会得到这个小的Fix选项。
修复将为您修复错误。
现在，它并不总是能解决它
正是您想要的方式，因此它并非始终有效。
而且并不总是有“修复”选项。
因为有时无法弄清楚
如何解决您的问题。
但是在这里确实有效。
如果我点击“修复”，它实际上会添加一个参数
创建CardView
设置此变量为isFaceUp。
所以，如果我在这里说假，
它将初始化该变量。
让我们继续。
在那里。
错误，面朝上是错误的。
这被初始化为false。
所有这些都没有面子。
现在，希望您对这种模式很熟悉。
与此模式相同。
在这里，我正在创建一个ZStack。
它可能有一些变种。
不一定是因为还有其他方法
传递这些变量。
但是它可能有一个名为cornerRadius的变量。
因此，这迫使我们进行设置，
定义它是因为我们不能拥有未设置的变量。
这是同样的事情。
好的，就是这个讲座。
在下一讲中
我实际上将从一些幻灯片开始，
一些概念性的东西。
然后，我们将回到本演示。
通常我会告诉你更多
关于下一场演讲将会发生什么。
除了我要发表第二讲
以及第一堂课。
因此，如果您真的想看看第二讲的内容，
马上去看吧。
-[播音员]有关更多信息，请访问stanford.edu。
(regal music)
- [Announcer] Stanford University.
- Welcome to Stanford CS193p.
This is spring quarter of 2020.
I'm Paul Hegarty, and I'm
going to be your tour guide
for this adventure into
developing applications
for iOS using SwiftUI.
And it's gonna be quite
an adventure this quarter
because none of you are
here on campus with me
which is kind of sad for me.
It's gonna be a little bit strange.
I'm sure it's gonna be
very strange for you all.
And it's not really
gonna affect us that much
in this course, believe it or not,
because most of the communication
that happens between
you and me is happening
via our class forums, Piazza.
So you definitely wanna get on Piazza
and ask questions there.
Don't be shy about that.
We get very quick responses here.
See what your fellow
students are asking also.
And definitely be
looking for posts from me
because all course
materials, all announcements
are gonna be made through Piazza.
So don't miss that part of it.
Now, all the lectures
are gonna be pre-recorded
just like this one.
And that's gonna be
convenient for you I guess
because after they come out,
you can watch them at your leisure
and fast forward and rewind.
And especially since I'm going
to be doing a lot of demos,
that is gonna be really valuable.
I guess it's also gonna
have a great benefit
which is that as we do
many times in this course,
we release the course out
into the world for free.
So people can watch this.
Spy on us basically here
as we're doing this course at Stanford.
And we'll be doing that again
after we do the standard closed captioning
and other post-production work.
So if you're watching me outside Stanford,
welcome to you as well.
Now, of course you're not
gonna be able to participate
in the forums with the rest
of the Stanford students
because you're watching
this a little bit later.
But there are community-based resources
for asking questions
out there in the world
like Stack Overflow.
So definitely go and
check those out as well.
This SwiftUI thing is brand new,
literally just a few months old.
So you are on the cutting
edge of technology
when it comes to developing
applications for iOS.
And as you learn this,
some things are gonna be familiar to you.
There's a little bit
of object-oriented programming in there.
This language that you're
gonna learn is kind of C-like.
It shares some syntax with
languages like Java as well.
So that'll be familiar.
But you're probably gonna be learning
some pretty much brand
new stuff for you as well.
For example, you're gonna be learning
a new programming language, Swift.
Entirely new for almost
all of you, I'm sure.
And this programming language,
while it supports
object-oriented programming,
it also supports a different
kind of programming
called functional programming
or protocol-oriented programming.
And that I'm not gonna assume you know.
So I'm gonna be teaching you
all about that along the way.
The user interface paradigm is
also what's called reactive.
And it's declarative
rather than imperative.
And I'm gonna explain what all that means
so that's gonna be new to you.
And there might be some other
miscellaneous new topics.
For example, I'm hoping to get to cover
iOS's object-oriented database
which is really cool technology.
But in any case, all that you're
gonna learn in this course
is really just kind of a survey course
or a collection of real-life application
of stuff you're learning in
your other CS classes here.
For example computer-human
interfaces, obviously.
API design and language design.
Animation, persistence,
networking, multithreading,
all these things listed here
are absolutely going to be things
that we include in this course.
And so you're gonna see it all together
in a real-world environment.
So let's talk a little bit about
the mechanics of the course
like how it's actually gonna play out.
And in these pre-recorded lectures,
I'm gonna try and spend
most of my time doing demos.
I really believe in demos.
I think they make the
concepts very concrete.
So I'll probably spent around
2/3 of the time on demos.
But occasionally I do have
to go to the lecture slides.
And this is to cover concepts
that if you didn't understand them,
the demos might just not make any sense.
So for example, at the
beginning of lecture two,
I'm gonna be covering
MVVM, the design paradigm
we use to organize our code.
I'm also gonna be covering
the type system in Swift
'cause that's just so
critical to understanding
how Swift works, to
understand its type system.
But again, if I can, I
always lean towards the demo
because we wanna spend our time
actually doing iOS development.
That's what we're here to learn.
For your part, you are going
to have some reading to do
the first three weeks.
This is mostly to learn
the language, Swift.
There's an online Swift
programming reference manual
that I'm going to guide you
through those first three weeks
to try and get you efficiently through it.
Because it's a rather large document
and I don't want you to be spending
an inordinate amount of time there.
But by the same token,
you do have to know Swift
to be able to do SwiftUI.
There will be programming
assignments of course.
They are usually about a week long.
There's four or five of them.
This quarter's a little bit
short, starting a week late.
So these four or five
programming assignments
will be in the first six weeks.
And the reason for that is
I leave the last three weeks
for you to work on a final project.
And this final project is the culmination
of everything you've learned,
so we won't have any
programming assignments
during that final three weeks.
If you go to the online
forums, the class forums,
there's a lot more
information there as well.
And the syllabus is posted there
so I encourage you to read that
if you haven't already.
Hopefully, you have.
Let's get started here
building our first app.
I have a little video that I've made
of what this first app that
we're gonna build looks like.
So this is what it looks like.
It's a card matching game.
Those of you who have
seen this course on video
in the past will recognize it.
But of course this one's
all written in SwiftUI
so it's a completely new app.
And it's got a lot more
features than the previous ones.
Some things are really
easy to do in SwiftUI.
So you can see this
has a lot of animation.
These cards are flipping over.
Numbers are flying up and down
as you match and mismatch cards.
You've got that little colored ring
that's kind of spinning
down in the background.
So we're gonna be doing a lot
of animation in this course.
Animation is very important
to a good mobile UI.
You can also see that
this application's got
multiple themes, different colors.
We had that Halloween version.
Here we have these flags.
Our cards are just showing emojis.
Obviously my little video there
is going very quickly clicking around,
but you are watching it on video
so you can just back up and pause
and take a close look at
some of the animations
and the things that are going on there.
So that's what we're gonna spend
the first really two
or three weeks in demo
and in your homework, working
on building this application.
By the way, you're
probably not gonna see me
on camera much the rest of the quarter
'cause we're gonna be
doing screen records.
So you'll just hear my disembodied voice.
By the way, my disembodied voice
will sound a little different
because I'm gonna use my AirPods
when I'm doing the screen recordings.
It picks up less of the mouse clicking
and the keyboard tapping and all that.
So if you don't see me again
the rest of the quarter,
just enjoy my disembodied voice.
So all the work that we do
is going to be in an
application called Xcode.
It's the development environment for iOS
and it's all inclusive.
It includes the source-code
editing compiler,
debugger, it's all in one place.
And you can get it for
free from the App Store
if you just go on your
Mac to the App Store
and search for Xcode.
You're gonna find it's
probably the very first match.
you can see it right here.
And when you launch Xcode,
it's gonna look like this.
Now, your first required task
of your very first assignment
is to reproduce everything that I'm doing
in the first two lectures.
So you might wanna pause this
video and go download Xcode
and be ready to follow along with me.
Or you can just watch this
video at your leisure,
kind of soak it all in and then go back
and rewind, fast forward through it
to satisfy that first required task.
So here this splash screen,
it has two sides to it.
This is Recent Projects
which will build up
as the quarter goes along.
And then over here is essentially
how we get into a project.
And we're gonna choose
this second line right here
to create a new Xcode project.
Now, Xcode can be used
as we mentioned earlier,
not just for iOS apps but also Watch apps
and Apple TV apps, even just Mac apps.
We're gonna focus on building
iOS apps in this course,
but everything that you're
learning about SwiftUI,
it's applicable to all these
other platforms as well.
Now, these icons here
are all just templates.
Essentially, prepackaged
little bits of code
to get you started with
apps of certain types.
But we're gonna be
choosing Single View App
I think for every app this quarter.
And it's the simplest of the templates
and you're gonna see it
really doesn't generate
a lot of code to get you started.
And so let's just double-click on that.
Now, it wants to know
some interesting things
about your app, most notably the name.
So I'm gonna call it Memorize.
For those of you who
might be watching this
who have seen previous videos
of the quarters in the
past of this course,
you'll know that I did this
memory matching game before.
Not in SwiftUI obviously,
because that's brand new.
And I called it Concentration
instead of Memorize.
And I did that for a reason
here, used a different name
so that if we wanna refer
to it, I can mention it.
And when I say Concentration,
I mean the old non-SwiftUI version.
And doing the same app is
gonna allow those of you
who maybe already know some UIKit
or have some experience doing that
to compare and contrast what it looks like
to do it in SwiftUI.
So this second thing right here, team,
that's your development team.
In this case it's a
personal team, just me.
And when you launch Xcode,
this is probably gonna say
something like Add Team.
And when you click on it, all
you'll need is any Apple ID
and you can create your own team.
If you worked for a company,
it could possibly be a
company development team here.
The organization name,
this is gonna be your name.
This is going to appear
at the top of files,
written by CS193p instructor.
So you wanna put your name there.
This wants to be a very
unique identifier of you.
So if you're a Stanford student,
I recommend using this
reverse DNS notation.
edu.stanford.yoursunetid
is probably good enough
to identify you.
You could put the CS193p
in there if you want.
If you're a Stanford student,
it probably doesn't matter.
If you're not a Stanford student
and you're watching this,
maybe your email address reversed
or your company's address reversed.
You just wanna make sure it's unique.
You wouldn't wanna pick something
that someone else might also be choosing.
You could see that Xcode
makes this unique identifier
for your app out of these two things.
And then we're gonna choose the language.
The underpinnings of what is in iOS,
it was all written in this
language, Objective-C,
which is this
object-oriented version of C.
But about five or six years ago,
Apple came out with this
new language, Swift,
which is awesome because
it's completely compatible
with Objective-C.
So all their existing
libraries all just worked.
But it introduced a lot of
modern language features,
especially support for
functional programming
as opposed to object-oriented programming.
Swift does both and you're
really gonna see that
in SwiftUI because SwiftUI is based on
functional programming, not
object-oriented programming.
So I don't have time to
teach you two languages,
I barely have time to
teach you one new one.
So we are only going to
be programming in Swift.
And of course SwiftUI is all
using Swift, based on Swift.
This other user interface choice
is if you wanna develop in the old way,
the non-SwiftUI way.
I'll often call this
UIKit instead of SwiftUI.
We're gonna do all our
development in SwiftUI,
although the last week
or two of the quarter,
hopefully I'll have time to show you
how to integrate the
old stuff into SwiftUI.
Because SwiftUI doesn't
cover all the ground
that the old UIKit does.
So it's nice to be able to
kind of glue it in there.
And so there's some good glue in SwiftUI
to glue the UIKit stuff in.
These other switches in the bottom,
we might get time by
the end of the quarter
to do this Core Data.
It's an object-oriented database.
I'm hoping to have time to do that.
Unfortunately, I'm probably
not gonna have time
to do this testing framework.
Which really I don't want
that to make it sound like
testing is not important.
It's super important.
It's just that you can't
really test something
until you know how to develop for it
and we're just gonna run out of time
before I can go back and cover that.
So for our first assignment,
we're not gonna be doing any of these
so you can leave all of that unchecked.
So I hit Next here and
now it wants to know,
"Okay, great, you wanna create this app.
"Where do you wanna put it?"
And I strongly recommend
putting it in a folder
called Developer in your home directory.
That is kind of the canonical
place that we put things.
And I recommend strongly that you do that.
Down here at the bottom
you can see this Source Control thing.
Source control for those of you
who are not familiar with it,
it's a way for you to manage
the changes to your code,
kind of check them in and check them out.
It's especially valuable
when you have a team
because a team's working on the same code,
their changes might conflict or whatever.
So you wanna have a mechanism
for arbitrating those changes.
And so you can have this checked or not.
I'm not gonna have it checked here.
Later in the quarter I'll try to go
through some of the features
of the source control integration
in Xcode 'cause it's pretty cool.
But for now, either way is fine.
So this is gonna create our first app.
Now, many of you are not familiar
with this whole user interface here,
this Xcode user interface.
So I'm gonna go through it briefly
and I'm gonna start in
the upper-left hand corner
right here, this little row of buttons.
This is essentially how we're
going to run our application.
Now, if you click on this button here,
you can see that you can run
your application on a device
if you have it actually
connected to your Mac
which I don't currently have.
Or you can run it in a simulator.
And these simulators are pretty amazing.
They're a pretty full simulation
that I'm gonna show you in a second here.
And I'm in fact gonna pick
iPhone 11 as my simulator.
And I can just run this SwiftUI app
that this template created
for me by clicking Play.
So when I click the Play button,
it's gonna launch the simulator.
Now, the first time you do this,
it's gonna take a little bit of time
because the simulator
fully simulates the device.
And in fact I'll show you that.
So here's our app, it
says, "Hello, World!"
You can probably can imagine
from this code over here.
And that's what all first apps
do, they say "Hello, World."
But if we swipe up from the bottom
just like on a real device,
you can see that there
is the App Chooser here
and I can go into Settings.
Here's the Settings app
and I could set settings
about my device, et cetera.
It's not 100% a full device,
but it's the parts of
the device you would need
to make sure your app is really working.
I don't know if you also
notice that this device
is similar, it happens to be in Dark Mode
which is new in iOS 13.
And I'm gonna leave it in Dark Mode
because we're gonna wanna look at our app
in both Dark Mode and non-Dark Mode.
And SwiftUI handles most of that for us.
So I'm just gonna go back
to the App Switcher here
and switch back to our app.
Here it is, it says, "Hello, World!"
Let's go back and see how we got to this.
How we get to this whole
Hello, World business.
So I'm gonna press this square right here.
This is Stop, that stops the simulator.
And let's continue looking at Xcode's UI.
On the left here, this little blue area
which we can resize to what we want.
It's called the Navigator.
And it lets you navigate by file.
So you can click on files in here.
But it also lets you navigate
in all these other ways along the top.
Like you can navigate by searching.
You can navigate your
breakpoints in the debugger.
You can navigate through
all your old builds,
the outputs from your
old builds, et cetera.
So you're really gonna get
used to using the Navigator
to move around inside your app,
find the things you want, et cetera.
Now, in the right-hand side,
there's this gray area here.
This is called the Utilities window
or the Inspector sometimes we call it.
And we really don't need that very much
for our first couple of lectures.
So I'm actually gonna use this opportunity
to show you how to hide it.
If you look at these three
buttons in the upper right,
they let you hide and show these panes.
And I'm actually gonna
leave Utilities hidden
because like I say, we don't need it much.
You see there's a third button here.
This actually brings
something up from the bottom.
This is your debugger and
your console output down here.
I tend to leave those off screen
just because they're
wasting screen real estate
if I'm not actually debugging.
Also, they'll often come up
automatically on their own
when you for example, hit a
breakpoint in the debugger
or some output comes out on the console.
And this area is the main editing window.
And you can see that it's
currently split in two.
And you can split this area in
many, many ways if you want.
That's what this little
plus button over here does.
It lets you add another, a
third editor on the right.
You can even add an editor on the bottom
if you'd like your split to
be top-bottom, et cetera.
So that's kind of our
tour of the Xcode UI.
Of course there's tons
of menu items up here
and we'll learn about them
as the quarter goes on.
But let's look at our main editing window
and see what we got.
We got this ContentView.swift
you see right here.
This is a Swift file.
So this is your first look
at the Swift language.
And I'm gonna start with
this little piece of code.
And what this little piece of code does
is it provides some glue
between your code that you're writing
and this little area on the right
which is called the Preview window.
See, it says automatic
preview updating paused.
And of course we have the simulator.
We can always run that
to see what our apps
are gonna look like.
But we also can see what's
happening in our UI,
kind of in real time, approximately,
by hitting Resume here.
And what this is gonna
do is compile our code
and essentially run it right here.
It looks like a little iPhone.
Notice this is not in Dark Mode
so the text is black on white.
And that's automatic, the SwiftUI
takes care of that for us.
And we can resize this too.
Maybe make it over here,
it'll have less space.
And this code that is
essentially gluing to it,
I'm not really going to
pay much attention to it.
In fact, I'm going to
move it out of the way.
And when you make a big edit like this
or you're moving a lot of code around,
sometimes this preview will pause.
You see, it's paused again.
No problem, you can just resume.
But a lot of changes you make,
like if I change this "Hello, World!"
to be "Hello There, World!"
you could see it's actually
changing it in real time.
So it depends on the kind of change
you're making to your code
as to whether it will update in real time.
And again, you can
always run the simulator.
Especially if you wanna see it
on lots of different devices
and things like that.
The simulator is always
available to you up there.
So let's take a look at the Swift code.
This is the entirety of the Swift code
that's specific to our app.
There's a little bit
of boilerplate up here
in these two delegate things.
We'll look at those later
but this is really
pretty much all there is
when it comes to doing this
Hello, World right here.
So let's look at the Swift code in detail.
First we have this import SwiftUI.
I'm sure you can all imagine
exactly what that is.
It's like include or
import in other languages.
This imports what's
called a package in Swift.
This package is SwiftUI.
So that's the big ol'
package that Apple provides
that makes all this SwiftUI stuff work.
So anytime we're doing UI stuff,
we're always gonna be importing SwiftUI.
Sometimes we're going to be writing code
that is not UI stuff.
In fact, intentionally UI independent.
And in that case, we will
not be importing SwiftUI.
We'll be importing a different package
called Foundation.
Foundation is kind of arrays
and dictionaries and strings.
And the SwiftUI package
depends on Foundation.
So if you imported SwiftUI,
you get that one too automatically.
So this whole thing is really
just three lines of code here,
not including the curly braces.
So let's see what it is.
This first key word here.
Notice all the Swift
keywords are in magenta.
We can always tell the
difference between Swift
and the things we do.
So this is a struct.
This is just declaring a struct.
Now, I'm sure you know a
language that has structs.
C and C++ and these
languages all have struct.
And the struct in Swift, just
like the other languages,
is a container for some variables.
But structs in Swift are
much more powerful than that.
Structs in Swift not
only can have variables,
but they can have functions
and they can also have behaviors
which we're going to see very clearly
right off the bat here.
So this struct, its name is ContentView.
So the name of our
identifiers are in green.
And Swift's identifiers are in purple
and the keywords again are in magenta.
So the name of this struct is ContentView.
And this is a very interesting little part
of this struct's declaration.
It essentially means that this struct
is going to behave like a View.
Or some might say it's going
to function like a View.
Or some would even say it "is a" View.
Although if I use the
statement that it "is a" View,
some people will think that's
object-oriented programming
like the superclass or something.
But it's not.
This is not object-oriented programming.
This is functional programming.
And that's why we may be more likely
to say something like a
ContentView functions like a View
or it behaves like a View.
And this is super important.
This behavior, View, is crucial
to how all of SwiftUI
works as you will see.
We are going to be using so many Views
in the next couple of lectures,
you can't even imagine it.
And we're gonna talk
all about the concepts
behind this behavior specification
using slides at the
beginning of lecture two.
In the meantime, we're
just going to understand
that this means that
ContentView behaves like a View.
A View is just a
rectangular area on screen.
So here I've put my mouse on this Text
and it's selected it
over here in the preview.
And you can see it's put this
blue border around that Text.
That blue border is bordering this View.
So a Text, it also behaves like a View.
It "is a" View.
And so you're seeing it right here.
So that's all Views are.
They're rectangular areas on screen,
both for drawing and also for multi-touch.
For swipes and taps, pinches,
those kinds of things
happen in these rectangles.
So that's what a View is.
So when something behaves like a View,
it's a rectangular area on screen.
So our ContentView which
behaves like a View
is this entire rectangle.
The whole rectangle that fills the screen
is our ContentView.
All right, if you are somebody,
some struct like this ContentView,
and you want to say that
you behave like a View,
you must in your struct
have this var right here,
this var called body.
I'll select it for you here.
So here's the declaration of var body.
So Swift variables, they
have the keyword var,
short for variable.
Although we don't tend to call variables
inside a struct like this vars.
We call them properties.
So you're gonna hear me use
the word property all the time.
It means a var inside a struct or a class.
Also, if we're doing
object-oriented programming,
we call them properties.
So the syntax for a property,
really easy, you got a var.
This is the name of the property.
Again, it's green 'cause
it's something we chose.
And this right here is
the type of this property
or of this var.
Now, this is a pretty
interesting type even in Swift.
Because it's got a little magenta keyword
in the middle of it.
Normally this type might
look like this is an Int
or maybe it's a String.
Or it might be a Boolean value
or it's an Array or something.
But in our case, it's this some View
which is kind of a interesting type.
What this essentially means
is that the type of this
variable, this property,
is any type, any struct, as
long as it behaves like a View.
As long as it is some View.
So that's what this kind of odd thing
means right here.
So if you wanna behave like a View,
you have to have a var called body
that also is another thing
that behaves like a View.
And you might be kind of thinking, "What?
"That's weird.
"So to be a View I have to have a var
"that is another View as my body?
"That makes no sense."
But you could kind of
think of Views as Legos.
So of course there are some brick Legos,
Legos that are like the
basic thing like Text.
Text is like a brick Lego.
But then you can put Legos
together to make something else.
And that thing that you put them together,
you could call that a new Lego.
It's like a combined Lego
or a more powerful Lego.
For example, if you were
building a Lego house,
you probably would make
little Lego furniture.
A Lego couch, a Lego kitchen table,
all those things out of other Legos.
And if you consider that
couch and the kitchen table
as Legos, then you're
putting those together
to make the house.
You could even then
have the house be a Lego
that you put together to
make a Lego neighborhood.
Or the Lego world, Lego universe.
That's the way we wanna
think of making these Views.
Now, the difference
between a Lego and a View
is that there are special kinds of Views
that are used to combine Legos.
We've got these basic
brick Legos like Text.
And then we've got other kinds of Views
that are combiners, Lego
combiners, View combiners.
And you're gonna see us
use those in detail here.
That's why our body just returns
one single some View of some sort.
It might be returning a combiner.
If it returns a combiner View,
then it could have tons
and tons of Views inside
that are combined.
Now, this is also a kind
of an interesting var here
in that it's got this
curly brace thing after it.
This var, its value is
not stored in memory.
Instead this var is computed.
So every time someone, namely the system,
asks for the value of this var,
this code in this curly
brace gets executed.
And whatever the value that's returned,
that's what the value of the body is.
And every time it's called,
it gets called again,
it's constantly calling this thing.
Now, this code in here
seems kind of minimalistic
but it'll probably make more sense
if I put this keyword back.
This keyword, return, you see is magenta.
It's a Swift thing, it means return.
Return a value from this piece of code,
this little curly-braced piece of code.
And it wasn't there because
Swift loves to leave things out
and make it so you have to type
as little code as possible.
You're gonna see that later.
And so if you have a
one-line function like this
that returns a value,
so that's what this is,
a one-liner returns this Text thing.
Then you can leave this return out.
It'll just infer that.
But I'm gonna leave it in
because I want you to realize
that that's what's going on here.
We have this little piece of code,
it returns this Text thing.
And that's going to always
be the value of body.
Anytime someone asks me
for the value of body,
it's gonna execute this and
return this Text right here.
Now, this return type,
remember, is some View.
So if you're saying, "It's returning Text.
"What's going on here?"
Well, of course Text, it
says it behaves like a View.
So this is "some View".
In other words, somewhere
off in Apple's code
there is some line that looks like this.
"struct Text behaves like a View."
And that's why we can return
a Text as the value of body
'cause it's some View.
In fact, we could even
just type Text right here.
That would be valid because
to behave like a View,
your var body just has to
return something that is a View.
And of course, Text is a View.
So why don't we type Text?
Why do we do this some View?
Well, as our body of our
View gets more complicated
and we start using these View-combiners
and things like that, it's
gonna be constantly changing.
Which kind of View we're returning.
Right now we're returning a Text.
But eventually we're gonna be returning
View-combining Views.
And we wanna let the compiler
figure it out for us.
So this some View is basically
saying to the compiler,
"Go look in my code right here.
"Figure out what it's returning.
"Make sure that it behaves like a View.
"And then use that as
the type of the body."
You're gonna find as we
go through this course
that Swift is what's called a
very strongly-typed language.
That means every variable
has a specific type.
It's not a language
like JavaScript or other
where it's like well, the variable
depends on what you assign to it.
That's when it gets ...
No, in Swift, every
variable has a specific type
and always has a value.
That's just fundamental
to the way Swift works.
So let's look at this Text right here.
We create this Text.
Anytime we're creating
anything, any struct,
so a Text is just a struct
that behaves like a View.
And anytime we create
one, we in parentheses
give it whatever information
it needs to create itself.
Now, obviously for a Text,
it needs the string that it's
going to use to create itself.
and that's why you get
this "Hello There, World!"
And notice if I edit this,
it's not changing this.
That's because it's paused up here.
But if I resume, then it's going
and now I can for example
type, and it's tracking it.
So this is always the way we
create new structs of any kind.
We put parentheses after it
and then we give it
whatever arguments it wants.
And some things when you're creating them,
can take different kinds of arguments
depending on what they are.
And you're gonna see
that pretty soon here.
So let's see if we can start building
a UI that looks a little
bit more like a card.
Right now it just says, "Hello, World!"
Let's remind ourselves what
that's gonna look like.
Kind of a screen capture of the game
that I showed you earlier.
And our cards, they kind of
have these rounded rectangles
around the edge, you see that?
And this is a line.
Then kind of a white background.
They have an emoji on the front.
So let's take care of
each of these things.
Let's start with the emoji.
That's gonna be really easy
'cause an emoji is just a piece of text.
So I'm gonna delete that.
I don't know if you know
this but in any Mac app,
if you go to the Edit menu,
go down to the bottom,
there'll be Emoji &amp; Symbols.
You see there, I can get an emoji.
You can even search ghost.
There it is, ghost.
Let's double-click on it.
Now we have a ghost.
And sure enough, there's our ghost.
He's really small.
Although we can zoom in and see him there.
And we're gonna have to
fix that he's so small.
It's not gonna work for our cards
for him to be so tiny like that.
But one thing at a time.
The next thing we need
is our rounded rectangle.
So we need this rounded
rectangle, it goes up there.
So let's comment this Text out.
So I'm doing Command
slash by the way there
to comment that Text out.
And instead put our
rounded rectangle in there.
Luckily, Swift has an awesome thing here.
RoundedRectangle which
is exactly what we want.
And again, just like when we created Text,
we have to provide some information
to create a RoundedRectangle.
You can by the way, easily
find out what that is
by just doing the open parentheses
and Xcode will show you the options.
Now, RoundedRectangle,
there's four different ways
to create a ZStack.
You can specify the corner
radius or the corner size,
width and height of the corner.
I'm gonna do the cornerRadius.
So you can hit Tab here or
you can double-click on this.
Then it wants the radius
and this is in points.
So I'm gonna do 10 points.
A point is the same as
the point size of a font,
like 10-point font.
It's also, just to give you an
idea of the size of a point,
a typical iPhone is maybe
four or 500 points wide
and maybe seven or 800 points high.
An iPad might be 1,000
by 700 and something.
Now, I'm being intentionally vague here
because we never write our code
trying to know what the
sizes of screens are.
SwiftUI helps us write code
that works on any size screen.
It just adapts and adjusts
to any size screen.
You're really gonna see
that with our Memorize game
when we start having rows
and columns of buttons.
On big screens they're gonna be large.
When we're in portrait mode
it's gonna kind of resize things
one way and landscape another.
So we always wanna write our code
so it works in any size screen.
But that's the approximate size of a point
to give you an idea of a point.
Now, one thing that's
kind of strange about this
is this right here.
It has put a label on
this piece of information
that it needs to create a ZStack.
And that didn't happen with Text.
This doesn't say the string
or something like that.
Text doesn't have one of these.
But this is actually the norm.
It's unusual to have something like Text
where there's no label
here for an argument.
You have to go out of your way to do that.
And I'm gonna show you
how to go out of your way
although we're not gonna
do that very often.
Instead, when we create things,
when we pass the information,
we almost always label each piece.
And this is true when we
call functions as well.
So one of the things that maybe takes
the most getting used to in Swift
is that almost all the arguments
to all parameters of all
functions are labeled.
And this is something that was
inherited from Objective-C.
It's actually quite nice
because if we didn't have this
and we had ZStack 10,
I mean, is that the width and height
or what exactly is that 10?
But as soon as we put this
cornerRadius in there,
it's like all of a
sudden, "Oh, I'm creating
"a ZStack with a corner radius of 10."
It's kind of hard to see if
our rectangle is rounded there.
That's because I actually have
this line of code selected.
So we've got this blue line around here.
But if I just click away,
then you can now start
to see the ZStack there.
And if I zoom in, you can see
the ZStack quite clearly.
Obviously, we're gonna
have to do something
about the visibility of this.
Our cards don't want to be
smashed up against the edge
and they don't want to be black either.
But first things first.
We'll get to that in a bit.
The next thing I wanna do is combine
this RoundedRectangle
and this Text together.
Because remember, our cards
have both a RoundedRectangle
and a Text stacked on top of each other.
And I'm gonna have to do
that by returning some View.
So the View I'm gonna return
here is called a ZStack.
So a ZStack is just a struct.
It behaves like a View
just like RoundedRectangle is a struct
that behaves like a View.
So is Text.
Actually, so is our ContentView.
A ZStack does need an
argument to be created here.
The argument we're gonna use
is content then in curly braces
The list of the Views to
stack on top of each other.
And obviously we don't
need the returns in here.
So this is the list.
RoundedRectangle in the
back, Text in the front.
First thing in the list
and this is two items
but we could have five
or six or seven items
all listed in a row and
it would stack them all
on top of each other.
ZStack is just some View.
And in fact, this return type here
would be some sort of ZStack here
instead of a Text or a RoundedRectangle
or something like that.
But Swift is going to
automatically realize
that it's returning this.
And so it's gonna do that for us.
This kind of combiner View
is really important obviously
to building complicated Views.
And we're gonna build our
own combiner View next week.
So you're really gonna
understand how these things work.
Now, we're getting there.
But there's still some things,
we'll kind of resume here,
that this doesn't look much like our card.
First of all our cards
aren't filled with black.
They're kind of stroked with
orange around the outside.
Also we have a problem where
it's hard to see the edges
'cause they're all the
way out to the edge.
So let's fix both of those.
First of all, let's stroke
this instead of filling it.
And the way we're gonna do that
is we're going to call a function
on RoundedRectangle called stroke.
RoundedRectangle, we know
that it behaves like a View.
It has to behave like a View
or we wouldn't be able
to put it in the ZStack
like with this Text.
But RoundedRectangle also
behaves like another thing
which is a Shape.
Other Shapes are Circle,
Capsule, bezier paths,
these are all Shapes.
And Shapes can all be stroked
by calling this function
on them called stroke.
And you can see that it's
exactly what happened.
It stroked a line around the edges
of this RoundedRectangle.
And stroke is an interesting function
in that it returns something.
Can you guess what it returns?
It returns a View.
It returns something
that behaves like a View.
And it has to because whatever
this is has to be a View.
Otherwise again, we couldn't
put it in the ZStack.
So this right here is like a stroked
RoundedRectangle View
or something like that.
So there's two Views still in the ZStack.
A stroked RoundedRectangle is one of them
and Text is the other.
So this pattern of calling
a function on a View
or a Shape
to return another View is very common.
This is the first time you've
seen a Swift function call.
Really simple, it's just dot
and the name of the function.
And then in parentheses, any arguments.
Now, stroke actually can take arguments
but it works perfectly
fine without its arguments.
Without its arguments,
it just kind of does this default behavior
of stroking kind of a one-point line
around the edges of the Shape.
So what about the color
of this RoundedRectangle's edge here?
It currently looks like
it's kind of either
maybe dark gray or something like that.
What if we want that to be orange?
So how do we do that?
Well, this is a View
right here, some View.
And all Views, anything
that behaves like a View,
you can call the function on
it called foregroundColor.
It takes an argument which is a Color.
I'm gonna use the Color orange.
And that will set the
color that it uses to draw
to be this Color, orange.
And sure enough, look at that.
It's changed it to orange right there.
Now, this function can
be called on any View.
We could call it on Text.
You can see, no errors.
Of course, it doesn't
really help with Text
'cause it's an emoji.
But if Text were the letter X instead,
you'd see that that's
an orange X right there.
Again, it doesn't make
sense to call it there.
The other thing we could send
this orange to is our ZStack.
What does it mean to tell this View
to have its foregroundColor be orange?
ZStack is just a View.
It behaves like a View
so it has foregroundColor
just like every other View in the world.
And what it means for
this is "Tell every View
"inside of me to use
foregroundColor orange."
So this works as well.
Look at that.
See, that's orange.
Again, if we change this ghost to an X,
that X would be orange as
well because the ZStack
is essentially setting the environment
that all of the Views inside of it
are going to use to draw.
Now this can be overridden.
We could then say,
foregroundColor(Color.blue).
And then we'd get a blue one out here.
But this would still be orange.
Because I only overrode
this foregroundColor blue
for this View right here,
this stroked RoundedRectangle.
I didn't override it
for this X right here.
So by scoping the calls
to these functions,
so we can control what color things are.
And this is really valuable for the ZStack
because we're eventually
gonna make this ZStack
so it does the front of the
cards, the back of the cards,
everything in all those cases
that wants to be orange.
So we want orange for everything
so it's really nice to be able to set that
for the entire ZStack.
And we usually put these modifiers
for these combiner Views
on a line by themselves,
just to make them stand out a little more.
Whereas we might leave
them on the same line here.
Although occasionally,
we would even put these
on a separate line as well.
But we're not gonna do
it here, but you might.
It's kind of a style thing.
However you think your
code is most readable
and most understandable.
So we're making good
progress on our card here.
One thing, it's really
hard to see the edges here.
We kind of want some
padding around this edge.
And we can do padding
with another View function
called padding.
And here notice when I put
padding around my Text,
oop, it popped out, it got
some padding around it.
Now, I could do the same thing over here
to my stroked RoundedRectangle
since it's a View.
padding, ooh, that's nice.
You see, it put padding around there.
Again, I could even put the padding
around my entire ZStack.
It put the padding around the whole ZStack
which is probably what I want
'cause I don't wanna
have to put the padding
on every single
RoundedRectangle separately.
Like the RoundedRectangle we'll use
for the back of my card
eventually and things like that.
So this is nice to be able
to put these on the outside.
Now, notice the subtle
difference between padding
and foregroundColor.
Padding pads the ZStack.
The entire ZStack gets
some padding around it
and everything in the ZStack is drawn
in that little padded area.
Whereas foregroundColor
doesn't really make sense
for a ZStack.
A ZStack doesn't have a color.
All it does it contain other Views.
So it gets passed down
into the environment
for all the Views on the inside of it.
All right, let's see,
we've been looking in our preview here.
But let's go take a look in our simulator
to see how this looks.
And ah, kind of interesting.
It's working but it doesn't
look very good here.
That's because our
simulator's in Dark Mode.
And really we want this
background to be white.
Even in Dark Mode we want it to be white.
We don't want it to be black
cards on black background.
Let's say we want it to be white.
So how would we make that white?
Unfortunately, there's
no function you can send
to a RoundedRectangle that
says stroke it with one Color
and then fill it with another Color.
But that's no problem because
we're in a ZStack right here.
So I'm just gonna create
another RoundedRectangle,
and this one I will
fill instead of stroke.
And remember, it's in the back of this.
And resume right here.
Now, that's gonna fill it with
whatever the foregroundColor
that's set as the environment
here, so I can't even see.
But luckily fill takes
an optional argument
which is the Color to fill with.
And that overrides this
foregroundColor here.
So now this is white.
If I click on here, it
is filling it with white.
And there is that orange
border, kind of hard to see.
It's only one point wide,
especially near the black.
It's really kind of hard to see.
So let's fix that.
A stroke I told you could
take other arguments.
One it can take is line width.
So let's make it a line width of three.
Again, we could resume here
to see it in Light Mode.
There it is.
And we can run over here
to see this in Dark Mode.
And by the way, the dark and
light mode of your simulator
can also be controlled right here.
You see this little button down here?
You see this Interface Style?
You can turn that on and go
from Dark Mode to Light Mode.
Now if you go back to your simulator,
it's in Light Mode.
That's really kind of a cool
way to switch back and forth.
So we are making some great progress here.
Our little emoji is still really small.
I'm gonna make it bigger.
I can do that with Font.
Font, Font.largeTitle.
Now I'm using a pre-canned
Font here called largeTitle.
There's some other ones called subheadline
and body and other things.
largeTitle happens to be
the largest one I can find.
If we resume, you are gonna see
it's gonna make our emoji larger.
Still not large enough.
Next week we're gonna
learn how to scale the Font
to an exact size that
fits nicely in our card.
But for now at least it's
getting a little bit larger.
One of the reason I did this
is I also wanna show you that this Font,
while it seems like this
would be a Text only thing,
it can actually be put on the ZStack
and it will set the font
environment for all Texts.
So if I had multiple
Texts inside the ZStack,
then it would use the Font,
that Font for all of them.
And you could easily
imagine building something
that had multiple pieces of Text
and you want them all to be the same Font.
And so setting it on the
ZStack is a really cool feature
for that as well.
So I've kind of got the card
somewhat looking like I want.
Now I want multiple cards
'cause I only have one card here
and I'd love to have multiple cards.
So how am I gonna get multiple cards?
I'm gonna do that by returning
a different kind of View,
another combiner View.
This is called a ForEach.
Now, a ForEach, of course
it takes arguments.
The first argument, it
takes two arguments.
The first argument is like an
iterable thing of some sort.
We'll talk about that in a second.
Then the second argument, just
like a ZStack, is content.
And that content is
going to be this ZStack.
What ForEach is gonna do
is it's going to iterate
over this iterable thing.
And for each of those things,
it's going to build one of these Views.
So it essentially is a way
to make multiple Views.
Kind of a View replicator
or a View iterator
if you wanna think of it like that.
So what is this iterable thing
we're talking about here?
Well, usually this is
going to be an array.
So you're gonna give it an array of things
and it's gonna, for each
of the things in the array,
it's going to create a View.
I'm not gonna use an array here.
We'll eventually switch to using an array
but I'm using another
iterable thing called a Range.
So this is the Range from zero
up to and not including four.
That's what this Swift
syntax right here means.
It means a Range from some
lower bound to some upper bound,
not including the upper bound.
If you say dot-dot-dot, then
it includes the upper bound.
But I don't wanna include the upper bound.
So, this is going through for
zero, one, two, and three.
It's going to create this ZStack in here.
So it's a repeater.
Now, one thing that's also cool,
so it's got the same thing
where it's got the content.
And this could be a list of Views.
We only have one View
in here, it's a ZStack.
But we could have multiple things.
Just like in the ZStack,
we have multiple things.
The ForEach, its little curly-braced thing
could have multiple things.
And one thing that's kind of
cool also about the ForEach
is it actually has this little thing here
which we're gonna talk about
this "in" meaning at some point
But essentially this is
the iteration variable.
So in this case, this index is zero.
And then it's one and then
it's two and then it's three
as it makes the four of these.
Now, one thing about ForEach,
you'll see in the preview it actually made
four separate previews of it.
And that's because ForEach
is not a layout View.
It's not like ZStack.
ZStack positions the Views on screen
on top of each other from back to front.
ForEach doesn't do that and if you run,
if we were to run this in simulator,
it would probably put the View somewhere
because it obviously can't
simulate multiple iPhones.
But really the preview
is actually showing more
of what's happening where it's
creating four of these Views.
So it's showing you each of the four Views
that it's creating.
Which is really cool for debugging.
It's like, "Oh yeah, this is the one now."
Our four Views are exactly the same
so not so interesting for us.
But what we really wanna do
is put all four of these on
the screen at the same time.
And for that we need another stack.
Now, we don't wanna stack
them on top of each other
and we wouldn't be able to
see the ones in the back.
Instead we want a different one
which is we're gonna return an HStack.
Our HStack just like ZStack has content.
And you put in the content the things
you want to arrange like this.
And HStack instead of arranging
things from back to front,
it arranges things horizontally.
That's what the H means,
from left to right.
So look at that, left to
right, it arranged them there.
Now, I told you that Swift
likes to not type things
that you don't need to type.
And that return I can still remove
because believe it or not,
there's still only one
View being returned.
Being used as the value of this body,
some View, it's one View.
It's a HStack of ForEaches that
make ZStacks that's padded.
It has a foregroundColor and a font.
That is the one View
that's being returned.
Of course, HStack is a combiner
so it's combining things.
And ForEach is a combiner
and ZStack is a combiner.
But those are all inside the HStack.
Now, notice also that the HStack
when it sees a ForEach
'cause this could be a list,
we could say Text("hello")
So it puts hello in there.
And then this ForEach
is kind of like listing
each of these ZStacks separately.
That's why it does this.
So each stack is smart.
It knows if it has a ForEach inside,
then it wants to lay out
each of the ForEach things separately.
Now, another thing to
notice here is the spacing.
There's a little bit of
space between these things.
Is that this padding right here?
No, that padding is this padding
around the outside of HStack
'cause the padding function is
called on the HStack itself.
That spacing is actually
something the HStack is doing
and it has an argument
that lets you set that.
So here I've set the spacing to zero.
Or I set it to 50 or I
leave it unspecified.
A lot of times we're leaving
those things unspecified
'cause we want this spacing
to be standard spacing.
The same in all apps.
Same thing with padding down here.
We didn't specify anything
here but in padding
you can actually even do
padding on the top is 100.
Or padding is 10 on all sides.
But usually we go for standard
padding as much as we can.
Standard padding and spacing.
Now, I told you, remember
we took away this return.
There's another thing we can take away.
In Swift, if the last
argument to a function
or the creation of
something, so here's ForEach.
It has two arguments.
This and then it has this
as its second argument.
If the second argument
is a curly-braced thing,
then believe it or not, you
can get rid of the label
and put it outside of the function call.
So here's the ForEach.
So basically the creation of the ForEach.
And here's its second argument.
It's floating outside of the parentheses.
So this seems kind of crazy.
But actually, look what it
makes our code look like.
I'm gonna do that for all of these things
'cause this only has one argument.
So I'm gonna get rid of that.
And I'm gonna do the same
thing here for my HStack.
So that looks kind of a lot cleaner.
You don't have those contents in there.
And even more than that,
if you have no arguments,
in that case where you have
the little curly-braced guy
hanging out there, you
can remove that as well.
So that cleans up our code considerably.
And of course we're doing these ZStacks
and these HStacks all the time.
Now, if I wanna put this
spacing back, I could.
Spacing, zero, perfectly fine.
It's still the first argument.
This is still the second
argument to the HStack there.
So it's kind of a little clean up.
So our code is looking
pretty clean already
making these four cards.
We can clean it up even a little more
by factoring out some of our code.
This ZStack here is essentially one card.
Wouldn't it be cool if I
just created a new struct
called a CardView which
also behaves like a View?
Which means what?
It has to have a var
body that is some View.
And in here we just return some View.
I'm gonna return a ZStack.
Cut that out of there, paste it in there.
And then in ContentView here,
I'm just gonna create a CardView.
So this is a way we can use the Views
to factor out our code
to do encapsulation.
To make our code look
even simpler and nicer.
Somebody looking at this ContentView,
it's really easy to see what
this is gonna look like.
And similarly down here.
Simple to see.
Now, the last thing I'm
gonna do here in this lecture
is do fronts and backs of cards.
'Cause right now, we only have
the front of the card shown.
We don't ever show the back of the card.
So how would we draw
this back of the card?
Well, it's just a ZStack as well
but it's filled with the foregroundColor.
So we could actually go ahead
and just copy and paste here
a RoundedRectangle to be the back.
And for the moment I'll comment this out.
And of course we don't
wanna fill with white.
We just wanna fill with whatever
our environment Color is.
Which it's going to get from here.
Notice that this foregroundColor
not only applies to
everything in the HStack
that ForEach passes it on down
so that it applies to the CardView
which passes it on down.
Which applies to the ZStack
which passes it on down
so that it applies to all these things.
So now if we resume.
We can see backs of cards.
See, here's the backs of our cards.
Right here, RoundedRectangles
that are just filled.
But of course, really, we
want to have fronts of cards
and backs of cards somehow be conditional.
Or the card is either
face up or face down.
So we need an if-then or something.
Well, the amazing thing
here is that this ZStack,
which allows you to put
a list of Views in here
also lets you put ifs.
So you can put simple ifs like
if, let's say, isFaceUp for now.
And we'll put these three
things in the isFaceUp case.
And then, otherwise if it's face down,
then we will put this right here.
So we can actually put an if.
Now, we got all kinds of
errors and warnings here
because I just made up isFaceUp.
That's not a thing.
I just made that up.
What do I want isFaceUp to be?
Well, I'm just gonna have it be a var.
It's gonna be a normal in memory var.
It's not gonna have any curly
braces or anything on it.
It's just a normal in memory var.
And you see that fixed up
all of our code down here.
CardView is perfectly,
internally self-consistent.
It's referring, it's saying
if my isFaceUp var is true,
then this way, otherwise this way.
But it did cause an error up here.
And what is this error about,
missing argument for isFaceUp?
Why is it saying that?
Well, I told you earlier.
Swift, all variables, it's strongly typed
and all variables have
to have an initial value.
So we could set an initial value
by just saying it equals false.
And if I say that it's going
to fix this error right here.
Face up is false, does that.
And if I change thisFaceUp
to be true and resume,
now we get face up cards.
So that's one way to set this.
And we often will set
this if it makes sense.
But if we don't set it in here,
we don't give it a default value,
that's when we get this error up here.
Because Swift is saying this CardView
that you're trying to create right here,
it has an uninitialized variable.
So you have to initialize it.
And here's a cool feature.
If you click on this little
red button of an error,
a lot of times you'll get
this little Fix option.
And the Fix will fix the error for you.
Now, it's not always gonna fix it
exactly the way you want so
it doesn't work all the time.
And there's not always a Fix option.
'Cause sometimes it can't figure out
how to fix what you're saying.
But here it does work.
If I hit Fix, it actually adds an argument
to the creation of CardView
to set this variable isFaceUp.
So if I say false right here,
it's going to initialize this variable.
Let's resume.
And there it is.
False, face up is false.
This gets initialized false.
All these are not face up.
Now, hopefully this pattern
is looking familiar to you.
It's the same as this pattern.
Here I'm creating a ZStack.
It has some var probably.
Not necessarily because
there are other ways
to pass these variables.
But it might have a var
called cornerRadius.
And so it's forcing us to set it,
to define it 'cause we
can't have unset vars.
This is the same kind of thing.
Okay, that is it for this lecture.
In the next lecture,
I'm gonna actually start with some slides,
some conceptual stuff.
Then we'll get right back to this demo.
Normally I would tell
you a little bit more
about what's gonna happen
in the next lecture.
Except for that I'm releasing lecture two
along with lecture one.
So if you really want to
see what's in lecture two,
just go watch it right now.
- [Announcer] For more, please
visit us at stanford.edu.